bigupload.com 2008-12-17

# Bigupload — Privacy Policy

Bigupload is committed to protecting your online privacy. The following policy explains how your personal information will be treated when you register for an Bigupload account. If we are going to use customers’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify customers by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days.

This privacy statement covers the site www.bigupload.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users’ privacy. 

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact Bigupload's Customer Support group by e-mail at [contact us](http://help.bigupload.com/). 

Simply put, we are committed to providing you with the best service available online or elsewhere.

**What is Bigupload and why is my information needed?**

Bigupload provides customers with online storage space which can be used to store, share, access, and protect important files. Bigupload is web based, and we require, at a minimum, a first name, last name, password, and valid e-mail address. 

**What personal information does Bigupload collect from me?**

Bigupload collects personal information upon registration. When upgrading to a premium paid account, Bigupload will ask for your credit card information in order to provide you uninterrupted service. Please note that the more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once registered, you are part of the Bigupload community, a customer account is created, and you can take full advantage of Bigupload's services.

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including immediately following the registration process, when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by Bigupload, and when you report a problem with the service or with your account. If you contact Bigupload we will keep a record of that correspondence. In addition, Bigupload occasionally asks registered users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. A link is included to this Privacy Policy wherever Bigupload collects personal information.

Bigupload customers use our service to store files and folders (data). Bigupload will not review, share, distribute, print, or reference any such data except as outlined in the Terms of Service or as may be required by law.

**What are cookies and how does Bigupload use them?**

In order to provide a personalized service, Bigupload uses cookies to store some information about your account. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server that is stored on your computer's hard drive. Bigupload uses both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. These cookies are not tied to your personally identifiable information.

Generally, we use cookies:

  * To establish an authenticated session with the service when you login to your Bigupload account using our web interface. When you use Bigupload's web interface to access your account, logging in will require that you accept a session ID cookie. When you close your web browser, the session ID cookie will terminate.
  * To remember some of your basic account preferences in order to deliver a better, more personalized service. A persistent cookie may be set when you register, "Sign In," or use the Bigupload web interface to record certain application settings and other preferences.

Bigupload may also record your IP address for system administration, monitoring, and fraud prevention purposes. IP Addresses are not linked or cross-referenced with any personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Bigupload only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies.

**How does Bigupload use my information?**

Bigupload does not provide any of your personal information to third parties except as outlined in this privacy policy. We do not sell or give access to our customer e-mail list or other customer profile information to anyone except as outlined.

Bigupload does research on customer demographics and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, or from surveys. This information is tracked using log files, tracking pixels and database history tables. We do this to better understand and serve our customers. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis.

**With whom does Bigupload share my information?**

Bigupload will not disclose any of your personal information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see our Terms of Service for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.

  * **Data in the Aggregate** : Bigupload may disclose aggregated statistics in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.
  * **Special Circumstances:** Bigupload may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Bigupload's Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Bigupload's rights or property, other Bigupload users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Bigupload may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.
  * **Third Party Retail Distributors:** Should you signup for Bigupload through one of our third party retail distributors, Bigupload may disclose your email address to that specific third party retail distributor.

**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**

Bigupload may, from time to time, e-mail you regarding our products and services. Only Bigupload or agents working under confidentiality agreements on behalf of Bigupload will send you such e-mail. All announcements sent by Bigupload also include unsubscribe instructions.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to access your Bigupload via the web interface.

Bigupload does not sell or provide access to customer information to anyone, unless you happen to sign up for an account through a third-party affiliate, in which case that affiliate also has your e-mail address. If there is any other exception to this policy, we will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer.

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Your Bigupload account information and Bigupload customer profile are password-protected so that you, and only you, have access to this personal information. You may edit your Bigupload account information by logging into our web interface using your Bigupload username and password.

We require that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Bigupload will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail. Also remember to sign out of your Bigupload account and close your browser window when you finish your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information or files if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Bigupload cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or while using the service, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**What does Bigupload do with contact information that I might provide when sharing files or folders?**

When you use Bigupload to "Send a File" with someone, you normally enter that person's e-mail address into the system so that a message can be sent informing him or her of the share. Bigupload treats any contact information that you enter while using the service with the same respect and confidentiality as your own information. E-mail addresses that you enter when using Bigupload to share information are not sold or made available to any 3rd parties.

When you use Bigupload's "Send a File" feature, you can elect to have the system send a notification message on your behalf by entering the e-mail address(es) of the person(s) with whom you want to share the file. If you prefer, you can instead generate a web link to the file, which can be sent as part of your own message. Send a File notification messages sent by Bigupload are one-time only messages with the sole intent of notifying the recipient of the shared file.

**What else should I know about my privacy?**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Bigupload is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site.

Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible online.

**Additional Information**

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [contact us](http://help.bigupload.com/) page.
